<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AMRcloud</title>
    <link>https://amrcloud.net/en/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://amrcloud.net/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>AMRcloud</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>AMRcloud</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://amrcloud.net/img/amr-cloud-logo-text.png</url>
      <title>AMRcloud</title>
      <link>https://amrcloud.net/en/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>DARMIS-2018</title>
      <link>https://amrcloud.net/en/project/darmis-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amrcloud.net/en/project/darmis-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;organizers&#34;&gt;Organizers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interregional Association for Clinical Microbiology and Antimicrobial Chemotherapy (IACMAC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russian Society of Urologists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data are presented on antibiotic resistance of community-acquired uropathogens isolated from midstream urine samples of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adults with symptomatic UTI (cystitis, pyelonephritis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;children and adolescents under 18 years with symptomatic UTI (cystitis, pyelonephritis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pregnant women with symptomatic UTI (cystitis and pyelonephritis) and asymptomatic bacteriuria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The study design is similar to that of the DARMIS study (2010-2011)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;time-period-of-sample-collection&#34;&gt;Time period of sample collection&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;01 Jan 2017 - 31 Dec 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;geographic-location-of-centers&#34;&gt;Geographic location of centers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34 centers, 26 cities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Russia&lt;/strong&gt;: Bratsk, Voronezh, Yekaterinburg, Irkutsk, Yoshkar-Ola, Kazan, Kirov, Krasnodar, Nizhnevartovsk, Novokuznetsk, Novosibirsk, Omsk, Rostov-on-Don, Samara, St. Petersburg, Seversk, Smolensk, Surgut, Tolyatti, Tomsk, Ulyanovsk, Chelyabinsk, Yakutsk, Yaroslavl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belarus&lt;/strong&gt;: Gomel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/strong&gt;: Karaganda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;antibiotic-susceptibility-testing&#34;&gt;Antibiotic susceptibility testing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Determination of minimum inhibitory concentrations (MICs) by reference broth microdillution method (BMD) in Mueller-Hinton broth (according to ISO 20776-1:2006) at the central laboratory of the Institute of Antimicrobial Chemotherapy (IAC), Smolensk State Mediacal University (SSMU)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;interpretation-of-mics&#34;&gt;Interpretation of MICs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clinical susceptibility categories were assigned based on the European Committee on Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing (EUCAST) MIC Clinical breakpoints v.9.0 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eucast.org/clinical_breakpoints/&#34;&gt;http://www.eucast.org/clinical_breakpoints/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;study-group&#34;&gt;Study Group&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amineva P.G.&lt;/em&gt; (Yekaterinburg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Becker G.G.&lt;/em&gt; (Novosibirsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bulkin A.N.&lt;/em&gt; (St. Petersburg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bykonya S.A.&lt;/em&gt; (Tomsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chastoedova A.N.&lt;/em&gt; (Kirov)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Domanskaya O.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Novokuznetsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elokhina E.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Omsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ershova M.G.&lt;/em&gt; (Yaroslavl)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ivanova I.A.&lt;/em&gt; (Yoshkar-Ola)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Khaidarshina N.E.&lt;/em&gt; (Chelyabinsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Khusnutdinova T.A.&lt;/em&gt; (St. Petersburg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kogan M.I.&lt;/em&gt; (Rostov-on-Don)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kulchavenya E.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Novosibirsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lavrinenko A.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Kazakhstan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lyamin A.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Samara)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Malev I.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Smolensk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Malyavin A.I.&lt;/em&gt; (Ulyanovsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Martyanova N.M.&lt;/em&gt; (Tolyatti)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moskvitina E.N.&lt;/em&gt; (Seversk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mutin M.Yu.&lt;/em&gt; (Bratsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naboka Yu.L.&lt;/em&gt; (Rostov-on-Don)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nikiforovskaya N.N.&lt;/em&gt; (Smolensk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Palagin I.S.&lt;/em&gt; (Smolensk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plugin P.S.&lt;/em&gt; (Novosibirsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Popova L.D.&lt;/em&gt; (Omsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portnyagina U.S.&lt;/em&gt; (Yakutsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shamaeva S.Kh.&lt;/em&gt; (Yakutsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shipitsyna E.V.&lt;/em&gt; (St. Petersburg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shirokova T.M.&lt;/em&gt; (Kirov)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sidorova R.K.&lt;/em&gt; (Ulyanovsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strebkova V.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Voronezh)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sukhoreva M.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Irkutsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tapalsky D.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Belarus)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Valiullina I.R.&lt;/em&gt; (Kazan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Varganova A.N.&lt;/em&gt; (Surgut)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Varibrus E.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Krasnodar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vasilyeva I.R.&lt;/em&gt; (Nizhnevartovsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vetokhina A.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Irkutsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volkovskaya I.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Tomsk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zhestkov A.V.&lt;/em&gt; (Samara)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;media&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;media-body&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h3 class=&#34;mt-0 mb-1&#34;&gt;Coordinator&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;h5&gt;Ivan S. Palagin&lt;/h5&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Research fellow&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Institute of Antimicrobial Chemotherapy (IAC),&lt;br&gt;Smolensk State Medical University (SSMU)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;ivan.palagin@gmail.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ivan.palagin@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;ml-3&#34; src=&#34;iac.png&#34; alt=&#34;Institute of Antimicrobial Chemotherapy&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research project: Veterinary monitoring and Risk Analysis of Zoonotic Bacteria Antimicrobial Resistance.</title>
      <link>https://amrcloud.net/en/project/vgnki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amrcloud.net/en/project/vgnki/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;russian-state-center-for-quality-and-standardization-of-veterinary-drugs-and-feed&#34;&gt;Russian State Center for Quality and Standardization of Veterinary Drugs and Feed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research Institute of the Federal Service for Veterinary and Phytosanitary Surveillance (ROSSELKHOZNADZOR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OIE collaborating Center on Food Safety, Diagnosis and Control of Animal Diseases in Eastern Europe, Central Asia and Transcaucasia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main activities of VGNKI are ensuring veterinary drugs quality, food of animal origin and feed safety, certification and registration of veterinary drugs, feed and feed additives, including GMO-containing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We present the data on antimicrobial resistance of animal zoonotic bacteria isolates from different regions of Russia to over than 50 antimicrobials from 12 different groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;object&#34;&gt;Object:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isolates of E.coli, Campylobacter spp., Salmonella spp., Enterococcus spp. taken from biomaterial of farm animals (poultry, cattle, reindeer, swine), food and feed materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;method-of-ast&#34;&gt;Method of AST:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broth microdilution (standard EUCAST/ISO/CLSI protocol), Sensititre veterinary custom plates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;breakpoints&#34;&gt;Breakpoints:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microbiological end-points – EUCAST ECOFFs (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mic.eucast.org/Eucast2/&#34;&gt;https://mic.eucast.org/Eucast2/&lt;/a&gt;, ver. 5.26), EUCAST Clinical Breakpoints (ver. 2019), CLSI Clinical Breakpoints (Standards M100S28, VET01S 3rd ed.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;methods-of-gene-analysis&#34;&gt;Methods of gene analysis:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whole-genome sequencing (Illumina Miseq).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;data&#34;&gt;Data:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bogomazova A.N.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gergel M.A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gordeeva V.D.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gritsyuk V.A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ivanova O.E.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karabanov S.Yu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Komarov A.A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krylova E.V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kulikosky A.V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lenev S.V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lobova P.A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makarov D.A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pleskacheva M.A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pobolelova Yu. I.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pomazkova A.V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prasolova O.V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rusakov S.V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soltynskaya I.V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sukhoedova A.V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yatsentuk S.P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can leave you questions and comments by e-mail: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:phorez@yandex.ru&#34;&gt;phorez@yandex.ru&lt;/a&gt; (Makarov D.A.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMRcloud: a new paradigm in monitoring of antibiotic resistance</title>
      <link>https://amrcloud.net/en/publication/cmac-2019-t21-n2-p119/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amrcloud.net/en/publication/cmac-2019-t21-n2-p119/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://amrcloud.net/en/privacy-policy/20190926/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amrcloud.net/en/privacy-policy/20190926/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Administration does not check the reliability of any information provided by you except as expressly permitted by the Terms of Use or Additional Terms and cannot consider its credibility as well as your legal capacity to provide it. Nonetheless, Administration relies on you to provide accurate and complete Personal Data and timely update it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using AMRcloud your Personal Data is protected and processed in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-purpose-of-this-policy&#34;&gt;What is the purpose of this Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In accordance with the Policy Administration informs you for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the information we collect;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how we use information about you;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your rights and obligations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-we-collect&#34;&gt;Information We Collect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By creating a user account on AMRcloud you provide the following data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email address - is required for creating a user account and your access to the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username – is used to communicate with you. When you grant access to your results of data processing for third-party users by a link, they will be able to see your username.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password – is required for your authentication and access to AMRcloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, note that Administration does not store passwords in the public domain and cannot use your user account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set cookies on each our webpage to collect anonymous analytics data. We use this information to help operate our resource and do not convey or sell it to any third parties. The information gathered may include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;electronic data (HTTP headers, IP address, cookies, web beacons /pixel tags, browser type, operating system, hardware settings, device information);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the time (and length of time) a page was viewed;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;information about the actions you take when using AMRcloud;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;information about your location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creation-and-sharing-information&#34;&gt;Creation and Sharing Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have the right to use AMRcloud to get results of data processing strictly in accordance with the Terms of Use. All materials created by you, including all uploaded and downloaded data, will be available only for your user account until you share them (“share the results”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can share information using two modes: public (access by any user) and protected (access by entering a password). The users you share with can see your results of data processing, as well as your username, but not email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration does not use the content you create and does not grant access to the third parties to it. Administration may gain access to your content with your relevant permission only (for example, to identify and fix service failures).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;service-usage-data&#34;&gt;Service Usage Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To improve our services Administration collects anonymous information about the actions you take when using AMRcloud. This may include the number of visits to AMRcloud and access time, interaction with the website (for example, clicks on buttons and links), IP address, device information, operating system, browser type, proxy server, mobile data provider.  A part of the above information may be temporarily stored in cookies. Each time you visit any webpage of AMRcloud, Administration gets the URL of the webpages you came from and the URL you go to next. This Usage Data is collected automatically and is used anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help collect anonymous usage statistics we use Google Analytics. To find out more about its Privacy Policy please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites&#34;&gt;https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-use-your-personal-data&#34;&gt;How We Use Your Personal Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration uses your Personal Data (email address) to authenticate and provide you the right to use AMRcloud and to access results of data processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration may send you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;technical notices (information about changes to user account settings including password reset, account deletion and so on);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support messages;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;administrative messages (information about any disruption, interruption and resume after a failure, updates or other information about your use of AMRcloud or the Security Policy).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot opt-out of receiving some categories of communications from us such as notices of significant changes to technical features or functionality of AMRcloud, the Security Policy or other Services policies or applicable laws. With your consent, Administration may periodically send you other messages about new services, features or functionality of AMRcloud through the email address specified by you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-rights-obligations&#34;&gt;Your Rights &amp;amp; Obligations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration will store your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Policy unless a longer storage period is required or permitted by law. Administration reserves the right to delete your user account including your Personal Data and created content in case of your violation of Terms of Use. If you would like to delete from our database any Personal Data you previously submitted to AMRcloud, you may submit a deletion request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may access your Personal Data processed by AMRcloud in accordance with this Policy unless otherwise is provided by law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may request to correct any incomplete or inaccurate Personal Data we hold about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have the right to (If provided by the applicable international law or law of the Russian Federation):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;request to erasure or remove your Personal Data or any part of it and/or to withdraw your consent to the processing of your Personal Data;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;request restrictions on the processing of your Personal Data;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;object to the processing of your Personal Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, you will be provided with other rights not specified above, as required or permitted by international data protection laws or laws of the Russian Federation. If you have any concerns as to how your Personal Data is processed, please submit a support request. If you would like to exercise any right mentioned above, please contact the Administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawful-processing&#34;&gt;Lawful Processing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collecting and processing of your Personal Data are based on the applicable laws, regulations or legal procedures. You give your explicit consent to the Administration of AMRcloud for collection, storage and processing of Personal Data by accepting the terms of this Policy or any related documentation (for example Additional Terms). You may withdraw your consent at any time. For legitimate business purposes, you may object to the processing of your Personal Data. In this case, Administration reserves the right to delete your user account as required by your objection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cross-border-transfer-of-data&#34;&gt;Cross-Border Transfer of Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your personal data is stored in the Russian Federation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration collects, processes, stores, retains, clarifies (update, change) and extracts Personal Data using databases and servers located in the Russian Federation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating-this-policy&#34;&gt;Updating this Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration has the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time in its discretion including in case of any changes in applicable laws or technical features or functionality of AMRcloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we make any significant change, including limitations and restrictions to this Policy, we will provide you with additional notice via email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Use</title>
      <link>https://amrcloud.net/en/terms-of-use/20190926/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amrcloud.net/en/terms-of-use/20190926/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-of-amrcloud&#34;&gt;Use of AMRcloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration of AMRcloud (&lt;strong&gt;“Administration”&lt;/strong&gt;) grants User а non-transferable right to use AMRcloud. AMRcloud makes it possible to upload files («files» or «data»), process, change, delete and visualize data and results of data processing as well as to provide and manage access to results of data processing to the third parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to upload and process data in AMRcloud, User must create an account. By creating an account, User acknowledges and agrees that AMRcloud displays her/his account name, but not email address, to the third parties with whom User decides to share the results of data processing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular functionalities and services of AMRcloud are available free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to use AMRcloud User will need an Internet connection. User is responsible for providing all equipment required to access the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration reserves the right to update or modify these Terms at any time and without notice to User. A new version of the Terms will come into force on the date of publication on the Internet at the following link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amrcloud.net/en/terms-of-use&#34;&gt;https://amrcloud.net/en/terms-of-use&lt;/a&gt;, unless otherwise provided by the new version of the Terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of disagreement with any new provision of these Terms, User must immediately stop using AMRcloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-rights-and-obligations&#34;&gt;Your Rights and Obligations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User has the right to use AMRcloud in her/his sole discretion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User acknowledges and agrees that she/he is solely responsible for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;her/his usage purposes of AMRcloud;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any content (data files and materials) uploaded by User to AMRcloud and its compliance with local, regional and international laws and regulations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any actions leading to violation legitimate interests of the third parties including non-property and other intellectual property rights;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any attempts on intangible assets of the third parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User is not allowed to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upload, send, transfer or allocate and/or distribute any material that is illegal, malicious, libelous, violates intellectual property rights, demonstrates discrimination against people racial, ethnic, national, sexual, religious, social characteristics, discloses the third parties&amp;rsquo; personal information or data, including patient identification data, violates the rights of or injurious to the third parties, contains improper advertisement, violates any local, regional and international laws and regulations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upload, send, transfer or allocate and/or distribute any material that Users doesn’t have a right to make available under any law or under contractual or fiduciary relationships/ content that is subject to any third party proprietary rights;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impersonate any person or entity, falsely claim an affiliation with any person or entity;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taking any action including technically aimed to violate normal functioning of AMRcloud;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use AMRcloud for commercial purposes unless User has permission from Administration;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use AMRcloud for any kind of illegal activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Terms is governed by and construed in accordance with the internal law of the Russian Federation without giving effect to any choice or conflict of law provision or rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;removing-and-blocking&#34;&gt;Removing and Blocking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration reserves the right to delete User’s files immediately, with or without prior notice from Administration in the event that User fails to comply with any provision of these Terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration reserves the right to suspend or terminate User’s access to AMRcloud &lt;strong&gt;with notice to User&lt;/strong&gt; in the following cases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User uses AMRcloud in any manner that would subject AMRcloud or other users to the risk of harm or damage;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Account has been inactive for more than 12 months;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User doesn’t mention AMRcloud as a system for processing and analyzing data while presenting any content generated with AMRcloud in public (e.g. in journal publications, reports at conferences);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://cmac-journal.ru/en/publication/2019/2/cmac-2019-t21-n2-p119/&#34;&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt; for citing the use of AMRcloud:  Kuzmenkov A.Yu., Vinogradova A.G., Trushin I.V., Avramenko A.A., Edelstein M.V., Dekhnich A.V., Kozlov R.S. AMRcloud: a new paradigm in monitoring of antibiotic resistance. Clinical Microbiology and Antimicrobial Chemotherapy. 2019; Vol. 21 №2. P.119-124.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of one of the above situations, Administration may send a notification to User through the email address specified by User. If the above violations are detected, Administration will have the right to suspend User’s access to AMRcloud. In case User ignores notifications or violates provisions of the Terms systematically, Administration will have the right to delete User Account, including all data uploaded to AMRcloud, results of data processing and created links, without additional notice and consent from User.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration reserves the right to terminate User’s access to AMRcloud or delete User account without notice to User in the following cases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User violates any of the provisions of these Terms or related documentation (except all the above situations);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User’s actions entail legal or regulatory liability and/or jeopardize the ability of AMRcloud to provide services to other users;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no technical possibility to contact User and to notify her/him about the above conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, in case of high load on AMRcloud infrastructure caused by sharing results of data processing through generating a link with AMRcloud, this link may be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;amrcloud-changes&#34;&gt;AMRcloud Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration has the right to change AMRcloud, such as change the existing or add new functionalities and services, at any time without prior notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;revisions-and-errors&#34;&gt;Revisions and Errors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All information and materials placed on AMRcloud may contain technical, spelling, typographical errors or mistakes in text, graphics and figures. Administration does not guarantee that any information, data and other materials are accurate, complete or correct. Administration reserves the right to change and correct any information or materials contained in AMRcloud without prior notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;copyrights-and-trademarks&#34;&gt;Copyrights and Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User retains her/his entire right relating to the materials uploaded by User to AMRcloud, including all copyrights, trademarks and other intellectual property rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User has the right to distribute results of data processing generated with AMRcloud. For citing any content of AMRcloud or reporting the use of AMRcloud for processing and analyzing data in journal publications and conference proceedings, the following &lt;a href=&#34;https://cmac-journal.ru/en/publication/2019/2/cmac-2019-t21-n2-p119/&#34;&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt; is mandatory: Kuzmenkov A.Yu., Vinogradova A.G., Trushin I.V., Avramenko A.A., Edelstein M.V., Dekhnich A.V., Kozlov R.S. AMRcloud: a new paradigm in monitoring of antibiotic resistance. Clinical Microbiology and Antimicrobial Chemotherapy. 2019; Vol. 21 №2. P.119-124.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User acknowledges and agrees with the possibility of hardware failures and malfunctions in AMRcloud software including those causing violation of access to data processing results or loss of uploaded data. User agrees that Administration has no capability to predict any technical failures and to inform User in advance about such failures or to eliminate the possibility of the resumption of problems. Such situations cannot be used for bringing a claim against AMRcloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User acknowledges and agrees that Administration does not verify or endorse and takes no responsibility for any data uploaded by User or results of data processing in AMRcloud (except as expressly permitted by User). Administration does not guarantee that the files placed on AMRcloud are in accordance with applicable local, regional and international laws and subject to all terms, conditions and restrictions, under these Terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User acknowledges and agrees that she/he uses AMRcloud on her/his own risk and  Administration does not assume and will not have any liability to User for any information, data or results of data processing placed on AMRcloud, including their accuracy, completeness, timeliness, validity, copyright compliance, legality, decency, quality or any other aspect thereof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User is responsible for any negative consequences arising from her/his use of any information, data or results of data processing placed on AMRcloud, including damage to computers or devices owned by User or the third parties, loss of data or results of data processing, violation of rights or any other damages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User acknowledges and agrees that personal account on AMRcloud is intended for her/his individual use. User has no right to transfer access to her/his account on AMRcloud to any third party on a paid or unpaid basis. If User account is accessed by more than one User at the same time, technical problems may occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration under no circumstances and without exception is not liable to User for any damages, arising from or relating to User’s use or misuse of AMRcloud or its functionality (services), including lost data caused by any technical failures or problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User acknowledges and agrees that she/he uses AMRcloud on her/his own risk. AMRcloud and all its functionality (services) are provided ‘as is’. Administration does not take on of any liability related to usage of AMRcloud and does not guarantee that AMRcloud will meet requirements and interests of User.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration does not guarantee that AMRcloud will function quickly, continuously, reliably and without errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration disclaims all warranties, whether express or implied, of accuracy of results or reliability of information from AMRcloud (including related web resources or services).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration does not support or control links or materials placed by User through AMRcloud. Administration is not responsible for User’s materials, including their validity, legality or any other aspect thereof. Administration does not guarantee storage of data uploaded by User to AMRcloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Administration reserves the right to impose any rules, limitations and restrictions (technical, legal, institutional or other) and to change them from time to time in its sole discretion without any notice.  Limitations and restrictions may be different for various categories of Users and they are defined by additional terms between User and Administration in full compliance with applicable federal laws, regulations and rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference to any website, product, service, any information of a commercial or non-commercial nature, placed on AMRcloud cannot be considered either as an endorsement or a recommendation of these products (services) by Administration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://amrcloud.net/en/post/invite-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amrcloud.net/en/post/invite-register/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently registration in AMRcloud is allowed after a personal request to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@antibiotic.ru&#34;&gt;support@antibiotic.ru&lt;/a&gt; only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, specify your name, occupation, speciality, and organization you represent (if any) in your request letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AMRcloud Administration will consider your application and will respond to you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
